<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-06-29T00:52:05+00:00</updated><id>localhost:4000/</id><subtitle>© 2017 Craft By Zen</subtitle><entry><title>Seven Degrees of Strangers: Third Separation</title><link href="localhost:4000/letters/season-three/strangers-3-Joe-Lazzara.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Seven Degrees of Strangers: Third Separation" /><published>2017-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>localhost:4000/letters/season-three/strangers-3-Joe-Lazzara</id><content type="html" xml:base="localhost:4000/letters/season-three/strangers-3-Joe-Lazzara.html">&lt;!--
![Insert new picture here](http://gallery.tinyletterapp.com/b7acb1dd09358f1ed19f16a562a005fc08d42511/images/94ff2d22-e9e3-40a7-958b-ece4b3921ae6.png)
--&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Evan prefaced Joe is someone who’s walked an unconventional path. Before diving
into the interview, I glanced over Joe’s butcher shop’s website. The only thing
that stood out to me was the shop was in Carmel, Indiana. I’ve never been 
there, and was curious to hear how Joe’s path took him there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;enter-joe-lazzara&quot;&gt;Enter Joe Lazzara&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joe Lazarra is Evan’s father’s, Charlie’s, best friend. Having nothing to 
really go off of, I let Joe talk about himself and how he ended up where he is 
now. Joe didn’t disappoint. If you ever talk to him, he’s a magnificent 
storyteller and has a very solid sense of self.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joe took me back to his Sicilian heritage. Generations of his family was built 
around the food. That’s where it all starts. His family’s bond is around food. 
His eldest brother’s 18 years older than him, yet his father got all 6 of his 
siblings through college.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In college, Joe studied Quantatative analysis, which during the mid to late 
80’s, was the thing to study and get a great job. Joe started off working at a 
software consulting job. Certain events led Joe into the telecomm business 
when his job took an unexpected turn. At the software job, the HR manager took 
the 401k pension to Florida and used that money to deal or smuggle drugs. The 
DEA and FBI took whiff, and Joe exited as soon as he heard, disentangling 
himself from that mess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was in sales with GTE selling to areas around the U.S. telecomm services. 
That was until Verizon bought them out. He worked for small business, 
start-ups, VCs, doing early work in VOIP and selling high speed Internet to 
homes. He was a top executive at one of these companies until the 2001 
attacks, and a struggle tech recession from the dot com bust, made it 
unreasonable to continue as head of sales. Surprisingly, that company still 
exists even with the executives gone 16 years later. It’s a sign the employees 
are more important to keep the ground running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, he consulted for a few years. But Joe grew tired on traveling 
around. One side-effect of traveling is Joe really loved food, and seeked out 
good restaurants. He was a frequent to some up and coming places, 
restauranteers thought he was a food critic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;butchershop&quot;&gt;Butchershop&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-connections&quot;&gt;On Connections&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;takeaway-message&quot;&gt;Takeaway message&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Love unconditionally”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-whos-next&quot;&gt;On Who’s Next&lt;/h2&gt;</content><category term="letters" /><category term="season_3" /><category term="letters" /><summary></summary></entry><entry><title>Seven Degrees of Strangers: Second Separation</title><link href="localhost:4000/letters/season-three/strangers-2-Evan-Roar.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Seven Degrees of Strangers: Second Separation" /><published>2017-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>localhost:4000/letters/season-three/strangers-2-Evan-Roar</id><content type="html" xml:base="localhost:4000/letters/season-three/strangers-2-Evan-Roar.html">&lt;!--
![Insert new picture here](http://gallery.tinyletterapp.com/b7acb1dd09358f1ed19f16a562a005fc08d42511/images/94ff2d22-e9e3-40a7-958b-ece4b3921ae6.png)
--&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;!-- How does the concept of weak ties from Malcolm Gladwell's book on
connections apply here? --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;enter-evan-roar&quot;&gt;Enter Evan Roar&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-does-evan-know-simon&quot;&gt;How does Evan know Simon?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Evan is close friends with Simon as long as he can remember. Their families were
part of the same club. Their siblings went to school with each other. And even
though Evan’s family moved to North Carolina, both families keep in touch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Evan says he goes back to Minnesota once or twice a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;design-dimensions&quot;&gt;Design Dimensions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Design Dimensions is a design firm specializing in exhibition design. Evan works
there as a designer alongside his boss. He has been there for a year and has
designed exhibits all over, including [EXAMPLES HERE].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-did-evan-land-a-job-at-design-dimensions&quot;&gt;How did Evan land a job at Design Dimensions?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a sophomore or junior at NC state, Evan worked as a student ambassador
running events for the school. Finishing his tasks less than the allotted time, which he said was many hours, he helped doing other tasks. There was a need to create posters, and when he worked on the graphical work, he discovered a propensity to do more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slowly, he did more poster work, eventually building a portfolio. He used lynda.com to learn the Adobe Suite. And graphic design was not his major. It was business development. He had stumbled into this field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come post-graduation, when it was time to find a job, Evan submitted his portfolio to Design Dimensions. Evan had just started @ an Accounting firm when the design company called him in. He thought it would be worth it as his current role was an internship that may not hire him full-time, so he went for the interview. The design company took a chance with Evan. His boss interviewed him not only on the merits of his portfolio, but also his taste in music and relationship to his college fraternity. His boss went to the same school and was in the sorority with close ties to Evan’s fraternity. And being in a small design firm, his boss wanted to make sure she could work well with her future co-worker, one of the requirements was to be able to blast music in close quarters. So even though Evan was not a design student, he got the job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Footnote&lt;/em&gt; there’s a similar story I’ve read in Jessica Hische’s book, “In Progress”, in which she describes her desk and workspace she shares with. Designers are selective in who they choose to keep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-have-you-learned-working-there&quot;&gt;What have you learned working there?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The short answer is a lot. One year is a lot to go through many clients. For example, last Monday, Evan could be juggling through 10 clients. His strong point is graphic design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Museums he works with generally comes up with the content and its the designer’s job to make it presentable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s Evan’s job to take a given space, like venues, museums, and exhibition spaces, and design the entire experience, from the look and feel, to the overall experience. It’s a small office and very long standing over the past few decades. The original founder still comes by even though he is in his late seventies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s only recently he’s been doing more back and forth with the client.
Normally, the client comes with the specs and the designer can work with it.
Occasionally, the client also wants to be the designer and put their two cents into it. It reminds me the first iteration of your work will not be your last.
Rarely is that the case with freelancing either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;additional-notes&quot;&gt;Additional Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Evan’s favorite font: &lt;a href=&quot;https://typekit.com/fonts/din-condensed&quot;&gt;Din Condensed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="letters" /><category term="season_3" /><category term="letters" /><summary></summary></entry><entry><title>Seven Degrees of Strangers: First Separation</title><link href="localhost:4000/letters/season-three/strangers-1-simon-gonedeck.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Seven Degrees of Strangers: First Separation" /><published>2017-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>localhost:4000/letters/season-three/strangers-1-simon-gonedeck</id><content type="html" xml:base="localhost:4000/letters/season-three/strangers-1-simon-gonedeck.html">&lt;!--
![Insert new picture here](http://gallery.tinyletterapp.com/b7acb1dd09358f1ed19f16a562a005fc08d42511/images/94ff2d22-e9e3-40a7-958b-ece4b3921ae6.png)
--&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the next installment of the Jear-Bear Letters. After a brief three 
hiatus, we’re back with a new series called &lt;strong&gt;Seven Degrees of Strangers&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The title is a play on “&lt;em&gt;Seven Degrees of Separation&lt;/em&gt;” where you are at most 
seven links away from knowing any random stranger on Earth. So if I met a 
stranger on the street, I could trace them to at most seven degrees of 
separation until I found a connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the course of the next 7 weeks, I will write about the conversation I 
have with 7 people, each one degree of separation away. You’ll get to hear 
their stories and experiences, and how I relate to them. At the end of each 
interview, I will ask the participant to choose the next person for me to 
interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s no set agenda of topics to talk about. You will notice similar themes as we progress interview after interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-are-you-doing-this-project&quot;&gt;Why are you doing this project?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facebook and LinkedIn capitalize on first, second and third degrees of 
separation. I wondered who are these people, and can I connect with them on a 
personal basis as much as a first degree connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m hoping to have a deeper understanding about connections. I define a 
connection as a friend I can hang out with. Throughout the series, we’ll find 
out what connections mean to other people. And hopefully, I’ll build a new 
connection by the end of our conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m also hoping to hone my interviewing skills. At the very least, I love 
stories and I want strangers to tell me theirs. Quite contrary to the popular 
advise not to talk to strangers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;simon-gonedeck&quot;&gt;Simon Gonedeck&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter Simon. He’s a fun guy to talk to. We know each other from DevBootcamp
back in 2014. He was my in my cohort, and one of the youngest folks to enter
the bootcamp. Incidentally, not the youngest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He recently graduated from University of St. Thomas, living in St. Paul /
Minneapolis area, working at his consulting firm, MG Web Partners along with
his twin brother Sevy and friend Johnny, who also went to DevBootcamp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simon’s a lacrosse player, total athlete. Got my ass in gear from HIT when we
were at the bootcamp. He’s recovering from an injury. In our conversation, we 
talk business. About his firm, MG Web Partners, about dealing with partners, 
and dealing with the business side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like myself, Simon’s got a lot going on in his life. I can learn a lot more by 
saying “no” more often and taking on fewer things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mg-web-partners&quot;&gt;MG Web Partners&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simon’s a co-founder of the web consulting agency, MG Web Partners.
Along with his friend Johnny and his twin Sevy, they run a tight operation
working with local businesses around the area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mgwebpartners.com/&quot;&gt;MG Web Partners Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-it-got-started&quot;&gt;How it got started&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simon started working at an agency creating websites for a substantially low 
pay for work they could be getting more for if his friends and he went out and 
tried on their own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an email I got from them last June.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;My partners Johnny Mulvahill, Sevy Gondeck and I have started a web design 
and development company called MG Web Partners.
We specialize in building businesses remarkable websites that deliver new 
customers and drive revenue.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We help three kinds of companies:
 1. Companies with outdated websites
 2. Companies with poorly designed websites
 3. Or Companies that just need a new website&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Most companies fit one of these three scenarios, so if you know of anyone,
please forward them my contact information and I promise we’ll take good
care of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then, they have worked with clients all over the area. With all of them 
graduated, Simon and Johnny are moving forward with the business while Simon’s 
twin, Sevy, is going to work for Deloitte in the fall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;continual-improvements&quot;&gt;Continual Improvements&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having Simon talk about his business reminded me how much we learn on the job.
A lot of early business pitfalls with consulting businesses came often. With 
every contract, they learned something new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, drawing up proposals have been a learning process. It’s better to 
make a proposal that’s less stringent and allows for flexibility with the 
client. And to make the process more transparent, the company uses &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.proposify.biz/&quot;&gt;Proposify&lt;/a&gt;, a website that allows clients to review proposals 
while also giving the business insight into how their clients are reviewing 
their proposals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Growing the business was tough in the beginning. They’ve tried driving around 
the area, trying to attract business by going door to door. But their best 
strategy was been word of mouth. Having previous clients tell potential future 
clients of their work has been more substantial than other techniques.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.invisionapp.com/&quot;&gt;Invision&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;on-writing&quot;&gt;On Writing&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the benefit of being a first connection is they know more about you. 
Because I’ve been writing the Jear-Bear letters for the past two years, I have 
some insight on creating a weekly writing habit. Although long time readers 
will know 2016 was a terrible year for me in weekly writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simon’s been one of those long-time readers, so as a follow-up in our 
conversation, he asked some advice about creating a writing habit, and how to 
get through writer’s block. One of his goals is to boost &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mgwebpartners.com/blog/&quot;&gt;his company’s blog&lt;/a&gt; by writing more frequently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And because I understand the context he’s talking about, I gave Simon a 
recommendation, although know that I think back on it, I have more than a 
single recommendation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Bird by Bird” by Anne Lammont
That book has been freeing to me. It taught me I can give myself permission to
write freely without having to worry about making the best piece of writing
from the start with the concept of “shitty first drafts”. There’s also much on
being successful as a writer, which is to say
don’t expect success. As counter-intuitive as it may be, that piece of advice
helped me release what I consider terrible writing to my letter friends. A few
of those letters have been very well received, like my “Caltrain Suicides” letter and my “Lost Keys” letter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sethgodin.typepad.com/&quot;&gt;Seth Godin’s Blog&lt;/a&gt;
If we’re talking about prolific, it doesn’t get as good as Seth Godin’s blog,
which he has been serving for over the past decade. He’s the prime example of
less is more, which has helped me in editing down my own writing much less.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Peer Reviews
Earlier on in my letter writing, I decided to open up each letter for critique.
I reached out on Twitter to see who could be my critique, and a few people
helped me &lt;a href=&quot;#shout-out&quot;&gt;(1)&lt;/a&gt;. I’d send a draft out, and they would give me some helpful criticism.
I remember Helin gave me some pointers about sub-headers, which I didn’t
initially like, but has grown on me.&lt;br /&gt;
Unfortunately, I stopped because my critiques wouldn’t come back before my
deadline, so I carried along hoping my audience would tell me. Turns out, they
don’t, so this project is to help me out further because I’m working alongside
an illustrator. While the illustrator’s primary job is not to be a critic, it
does help to have a second eye. Plus, if I’m really stuck on something, I’ll
drag a friend into it. Stephen King wrote in “On Writing” that his wife reads
through his novels before he releases them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;shout-out&quot;&gt;(1)&lt;/a&gt;Shout outs to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/helin_s&quot;&gt;Helin&lt;/a&gt;
and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/j12coder&quot;&gt;Isaac&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;growth-hacking&quot;&gt;Growth Hacking&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, Simon asked about Growth Hacking, even though he didn’t use those words.
“How do I grow readership?” I ask myself the same questions. For an individual,
it takes years to earn credibility. For a company, it takes referrals and
tailoring the message to potential new clients. And for that, you can be very
targeted in your approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking a page from Seth Godin’s book, Tribes…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Growing Traffic
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/3828382-tribes&quot;&gt;Tribes: We Need You To Lead Us&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Release on schedule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Newsletters: don’t take un-subscriptions personally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;take-aways&quot;&gt;Take-aways&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I asked Simon what’s his the thing he wants people to take away with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over-communicate with clients. It might not always be clear what they want.
Don’t do it over email. Do it over the phone or in-person, if you can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;follow-up-questions&quot;&gt;Follow-up Questions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simon got to ask me a few questions at the end.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="letters" /><category term="season_3" /><category term="letters" /><summary></summary></entry><entry><title>Intro to Webassembly</title><link href="localhost:4000/learning/webassembly.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Intro to Webassembly" /><published>2017-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>localhost:4000/learning/webassembly</id><content type="html" xml:base="localhost:4000/learning/webassembly.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;intro-to-webassembly&quot;&gt;Intro to WebAssembly&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://hacks.mozilla.org/2017/02/a-cartoon-intro-to-webassembly/&quot;&gt;a lengthy comic&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://code-cartoons.com/&quot;&gt;Lin Clark&lt;/a&gt; about WebAssembly,
I thought it might be great to do a deep dive with it.
Thank goodness the folks behind the project have a very nice &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://webassembly.org/getting-started/developers-guide/&quot;&gt;Getting Started&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; tutorial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;prerequisites&quot;&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To compile to WebAssembly, we will at the moment need to compile LLVM from source. The following tools are needed as a prerequisite:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m on OSX. Check the link for above for your prerequisites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Git&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CMake&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Xcode&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Python (2.7.x)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;compile-emscripten-from-source&quot;&gt;Compile Emscripten from Source&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Building Emscripten from source is automated via the Emscripten SDK. The required steps are as follows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-bash highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gp&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;git clone https://github.com/juj/emsdk.git
&lt;span class=&quot;gp&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;cd &lt;/span&gt;emsdk
&lt;span class=&quot;gp&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;./emsdk install sdk-incoming-64bit binaryen-master-64bit
&lt;span class=&quot;gp&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;./emsdk activate sdk-incoming-64bit binaryen-master-64bit
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;After these steps, the installation is complete. To enter an Emscripten compiler environment in the current command line prompt, type&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-bash highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gp&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;source&lt;/span&gt; ./emsdk_env.sh
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This command adds relevant environment variables and directory entries to PATH to set up the current terminal for easy access to the compiler tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note, the installation process will take a while. Go make yourself some tea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-bash highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;To conveniently access the selected &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;set &lt;/span&gt;of tools from the &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;command &lt;/span&gt;line,  
consider adding the following directories to PATH, or call &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'source  
./emsdk_env.sh'&lt;/span&gt; to &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;do &lt;/span&gt;this &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;for &lt;/span&gt;you.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;compile-and-run-a-simple-program&quot;&gt;Compile and run a simple program&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We now have a full toolchain we can use to compile a simple program to WebAssembly. There are a few remaining caveats, however:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;We have to pass the linker flag &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-s WASM=1&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;emcc&lt;/code&gt; (otherwise by default emcc will emit asm.js).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;If we want Emscripten to generate an HTML page that runs our program, in addition to the wasm binary and JavaScript wrapper, we have to specify an output filename with a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.html&lt;/code&gt; extension.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Finally, to actually run the program, we cannot simply open the HTML file in a web browser because cross-origin requests are not supported for the file protocol scheme. We have to actually serve the output files over HTTP.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The commands below will create a simple “hello world” program and compile it. The compilation step is highlighted in bold.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-bash highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gp&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;mkdir hello
&lt;span class=&quot;gp&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;cd &lt;/span&gt;hello
&lt;span class=&quot;gp&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'#include &amp;lt;stdio.h&amp;gt;'&lt;/span&gt; &amp;gt; hello.c
&lt;span class=&quot;gp&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'int main(int argc, char ** argv) {'&lt;/span&gt; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; hello.c
&lt;span class=&quot;gp&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'printf(&quot;Hello, world!\n&quot;);'&lt;/span&gt; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; hello.c
&lt;span class=&quot;gp&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'}'&lt;/span&gt; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; hello.c
&lt;span class=&quot;gp&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;emcc hello.c -s &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;WASM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;1 -o hello.html
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To serve the compiled files over HTTP, we can use the emrun web server provided with the Emscripten SDK:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-bash highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gp&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;emrun --no_browser --port 8080 .
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Once the HTTP server is running, you can open it in your browser. If you see “Hello, world!” printed to the Emscripten console, then congratulations! You’ve successfully compiled to WebAssembly!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s how my logs looked when running the program&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-bash highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;➜  hello-wasm emcc hello.c -s &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;WASM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;1 -o hello.html
INFO:root:generating system library: libc.bc... &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;this will be cached &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;/Users/Jeremy/.emscripten_cache/asmjs/libc.bc&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;for &lt;/span&gt;subsequent builds&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
INFO:root: - ok
INFO:root:generating system library: dlmalloc.bc... &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;this will be cached &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;/Users/Jeremy/.emscripten_cache/asmjs/dlmalloc.bc&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;for &lt;/span&gt;subsequent builds&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
INFO:root: - ok
INFO:root:generating system library: wasm-libc.bc... &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;this will be cached &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;/Users/Jeremy/.emscripten_cache/asmjs/wasm-libc.bc&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;for &lt;/span&gt;subsequent builds&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
INFO:root: - ok
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="webassembly" /><summary>Intro to WebAssembly</summary></entry><entry><title>The Problem of Rushing Through</title><link href="localhost:4000/letters/season-two/the-problem-with-rushing-through.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Problem of Rushing Through" /><published>2017-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>localhost:4000/letters/season-two/the-problem-with-rushing-through</id><content type="html" xml:base="localhost:4000/letters/season-two/the-problem-with-rushing-through.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://gallery.tinyletterapp.com/b7acb1dd09358f1ed19f16a562a005fc08d42511/images/94ff2d22-e9e3-40a7-958b-ece4b3921ae6.png&quot; alt=&quot;Jear bear letters admission failure 8&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-problem-of-rushing-through&quot;&gt;The Problem of Rushing Through&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Life moves pretty fast. If you don’t stop and look around once in a while, you could miss it.” — Ferris Bueller’s Day Off&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A thought crossed my mind. “Am I rushing to die?” I had this thought before. I used to brush it off. The Ferris Bueller quote encapsulates the essence of life, to open up to live. “Am I missing life?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, I have an urge to rush to the end. But I risk not thinking through consequences. Rushing through my day, I jump into solutions without thinking about other options and alternative outcomes. When coding, it’s jumping into a solution without thinking about intentions. The implementation could have an immediate problem within the technical details. Or it can have an ethical one. For example, if we have a selection input for gender, you may assume the world operates on a gender binary. That is not the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To rush is to deny room to be aware. And thats a decision. It’s my decision if I treat work like race to exhaustion. It’s my decision to rush out of the door every morning, without checking if I have my essentials, to catch the early train. It’s my decision if I prolong getting my eyes checked. It’s my decision to stop working out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These scenarios lead to stress. Our bodies give us indication of stress. I have made myself numb to some of it. When the neglect goes too far, the body prevents us from moving forward. I’ve been close to passing out the last time I pulled an all nighter at work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The past few weeks of writing about failures is a reflection of what I’ve neglected in my life and why I stopped paying attention. These letters are to kick myself in the ass and ask, “what I’m going to do about this?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say the solution is as simple as slowing down; be present. This is my invocation to begin. I’m standing firm not to neglect the mind and body’s needs. I will let that guide my present intentions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My hope is for my future self to read this. My hope is my future self has slowed down. And if he has, please follow up and tell everyone how you did it. And say Bueller was right.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="letters" /><category term="season_2" /><category term="letters" /><summary></summary></entry><entry><title>The Placement Problem</title><link href="localhost:4000/letters/season-two/the-placement-problem.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Placement Problem" /><published>2017-04-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>localhost:4000/letters/season-two/the-placement-problem</id><content type="html" xml:base="localhost:4000/letters/season-two/the-placement-problem.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://gallery.tinyletterapp.com/b7acb1dd09358f1ed19f16a562a005fc08d42511/images/f60b85ea-98ea-469f-9942-d15b84fd12f7.png&quot; alt=&quot;Jear bear letters admission failure 7&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-placement-problem&quot;&gt;The Placement Problem&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lost-keys&quot;&gt;Lost Keys&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the frantic rush of the morning, I’m scrambling many things. I’ve got to shower, eat breakfast, work-out, gather my things for work. In this scramble I inevitably ask myself, “where are my keys?”. If I was wise, they would be in my bag. If I was unwise, I start my descent into madness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my key’s perspective, it’s a journey through my room. First, they’ll be in my pocket, ready to open a door. Then they will be on my work table, eager to see me when I’m ready to leave. Then they’ll be on top of the drawer because I’m changing my pants. Then they’ll be god knows where because I was in the middle of another activity and decided to place them wherever was convenient. Then I’ll spend an inextricable amount of time looking for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s times like these I feel helpless to my lack of coordination. I hate my forgetfulness because I lack the foresight to place things in proper places. My keys have a place in my bag, and should always be there. And for the scenario where I don’t bring my bag, it should be in my pocket. But therein lies the problem. If I know I won’t bring my bag, where do I place my keys when I change my pants?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-system&quot;&gt;A System&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was working in manufacturing, we implemented a 5 step program to achieving lean manufacturing. One of those steps was setting things in place. In one scenario, say you use a hammer. You take the hammer from its proper placement, use it for a bit, then place it back. To make things easier, one of our technicians placed an outline of a hammer so it is easy to place the hammer in its proper place. The alternative is placing the hammer wherever, which would be harder for the next person who wants to use the hammer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this practice, I should be able to implement it in my personal life. However, I am rarely open to the idea of changing my space. This is prompted by a stubborn attitude that I should remember everything. Added to that, I find moving things around my room to be a chore. And it’s all over when I consider something to be a chore because I’ll try to wiggle out of it any way I can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;applied-system&quot;&gt;Applied System&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to they keys. Because I lack a system to place my keys in the same place for every scenario, I find it difficult to find them when I’ve placed them in a spot at the time I thought was memorable. I’ve thought about a cubby, or a bowl, but haven’t acted on it. I’m skeptic it works for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Question for those readers. Do you follow a system for placing your things at home. How do you remember where you put your things? Does your system cover all scenarios?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;addendum&quot;&gt;Addendum&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll be honest. After drafting this letter, I’m going to give the bowl a try. At least I can cross it off my list if it really doesn’t work. Then it’s back to the drawing board.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="letters" /><category term="season_2" /><category term="letters" /><summary></summary></entry><entry><title>The Loneliness Problem</title><link href="localhost:4000/letters/season-two/the-loneliness-problem.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Loneliness Problem" /><published>2017-03-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-03-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>localhost:4000/letters/season-two/the-loneliness-problem</id><content type="html" xml:base="localhost:4000/letters/season-two/the-loneliness-problem.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://gallery.tinyletterapp.com/b7acb1dd09358f1ed19f16a562a005fc08d42511/images/e95530cf-ed42-42c6-a8c3-6916b74ab552.png&quot; alt=&quot;Admission Failure 6&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-loneliness-problem&quot;&gt;The Loneliness Problem&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My bestie has a romanticized version of my life where I am a perky, social butterfly always engaging in social activities. This isn’t true. I spend most days alone when I’m outside of work. I tend to keep my personal life in solidarity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not averse to being around people. I’ve made the decision to be content being alone. My state of solidarity allows me to relish my life in different ways than super extroverts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In practice, I hang out with friends, spend time on the phone with family, and rest around a fire pit with my housemates. To my bestie’s credit, I am a social butterfly at social events. But those are anomalies in my daily routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wasn’t always at peace with this idea of being alone. I grew up in a large household where everyone shared everything. There weren’t enough restrooms to go around and weren’t enough space to spend alone. I was reliant on the people around me; I would get sad if I was alone too long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once, my grandmother took forever to pick me up from school. Turns out, she fell asleep at the wheel a few moments after she entered her car. This was before everyone had cell phones, so there was no way of reaching her. I was close to tears waiting at the school steps, contemplating whether I should walk home alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In college, I had times where no one wanted to grab lunch or dinner, so I would go to the campus cafeteria alone. I found the experience miserable because I didn’t socialize with strangers at other tables. My resolution was I brought food back to the dorm and eat in the common area instead where there would always be people hanging out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This habit continued into my early working life. I had some of these same fears eating at restaurants alone. In a conversation with my housemate’s cousin, she told me about her experience after beating cancer. She said she had no worries about being alone anymore. There’s too little time in life not to appreciate good restaurants, so if that means going alone, so be it. Her motto in life made me re-think the way I approach being alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And being alone doesn’t mean one-on-one time with your phone. Quite the opposite. I like to bring a composition notebook and write or draw if I’m in a restaurant. Or people watch. Or talk to the waiter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was on a business trip this past week. There was two days there was no one around to grab dinner with. I’ve used the “alone” mantra to justify eating alone. It was a great experience because I got to talk with a sushi chef and an bar tender about their experiences. Also, there was a lot of people watching. So the big lesson learned is not every activity alone has to be depressive. Look past your ego, suck it up, and enjoy yourself alone.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="letters" /><category term="season_2" /><category term="letters" /><summary></summary></entry><entry><title>Show Your Work - A Manifesto</title><link href="localhost:4000/blog/show-your-work.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Show Your Work - A Manifesto" /><published>2017-03-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-03-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>localhost:4000/blog/show-your-work</id><content type="html" xml:base="localhost:4000/blog/show-your-work.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;show-your-work&quot;&gt;Show Your Work&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;show-your-work-1&quot;&gt;Show your work&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it’s meaningful to you, share it with the world.
If it means something to someone else, your work has legacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;live-your-work&quot;&gt;Live your work&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your work has meaning when you have breathed life in it.
Like a blacksmith beating a piece of metal, you too beat your life into your work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;give-your-work-away&quot;&gt;Give your work away&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your work has copies, give those copies away.
If the original is worth something to you, giving your work away gives that someone a piece of yourself.
Memory may fade, but if your work is a legacy, it can stand the test of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;destroy-your-work&quot;&gt;Destroy your work&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every life and creation can be destroyed. Your work is no different.
If you set your work free, your work can be crushed.
This is not a bad thing. Nature is agnostic to the forces of good and evil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;notes&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The piece of prose is inspired by the book, “&lt;a href=&quot;http://showyourwork.com&quot;&gt;Show Your Work&lt;/a&gt;” by Austin Kleon.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="blog, post, work" /><summary>Show Your Work</summary></entry><entry><title>The Problem With the Rider and the Elephant</title><link href="localhost:4000/letters/season-two/Admission-Failure-the-problem-with-the-rider-and-the-elephant.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Problem With the Rider and the Elephant" /><published>2017-03-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-03-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>localhost:4000/letters/season-two/Admission-Failure-the-problem-with-the-rider-and-the-elephant</id><content type="html" xml:base="localhost:4000/letters/season-two/Admission-Failure-the-problem-with-the-rider-and-the-elephant.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://gallery.tinyletterapp.com/b7acb1dd09358f1ed19f16a562a005fc08d42511/images/17d7d676-0a33-4f67-8091-dfc9478c888d.png&quot; alt=&quot;Admission Failure 5&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-problem-with-the-rider-and-the-elephant&quot;&gt;The Problem With the Rider and the Elephant&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The emotional mind is an elephant and the reasoning mind is the elephant rider. The rider has limited control over the elephant. The elephant is heavy and not always willing to listen to the rider. The rider might not listen to the elephant and demand the elephant follow orders by sheer will. The internal conflicts come when neither can work together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was younger, I thought age tames emotion. But after years of watching my dad get angry at little things, I threw that assumption in the waste basket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been misguided by my emotional mind. If I thought about death, my emotional side kicked in and took over reasoning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about the people who will miss you. Think about your body decaying. Think about the future without you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even as I got older, those worries lingered. Depression set and anxiety attacks appeared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similar feelings arose when I received rejection letters from grad school, isolated myself from loved ones, and after nasty break-ups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;meditation-part-1&quot;&gt;Meditation, Part 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I tried meditation. I learned emotion can be examined and felt. My emotional side can overwhelm me, and I have fought the feeling head on. Instead, meditation says to examine the feeling and to let it happen. You achieve this through a non-judgment lens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I witnessed the elephant the first few times I meditated. I approached meditation through a book I read. It stressed posture, breathing, and examination of the body. After the second week, my rational mind didn’t see the elephant. It imagined the daydream version of it. Unable to relax as I had with the previous week, I quit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;seneca&quot;&gt;Seneca&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I applied philosophical thought to the response of my elephant. Seneca, Roman philosopher from two millennia ago, taught his pupils to engage in a morning ritual of telling themselves what was the worst possible thing that could happen that day. Imagine it in detail, trying to put yourself in your own shoes. Imagine what you will be doing, how you’ll be feeling, etc. If the worst were to happen, you would be mentally prepared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This exercise could be morbid, like imagining you or your significant other’s demise. This might be trivial, like getting angry at drivers who cut you off. Whichever end of the spectrum your imagination takes you, you are experiencing that feeling in a controlled dose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did this exercise a bunch at my last job. My manager pulled the rug from our projects a few too many times, and I kept feeling wrecked. In the parking lot before going in the building, I’d ask myself what’s the worst thing that could happen that day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could be fired. My project could be pulled. I could receive a demotion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And after a few days of this exercise, imagining what it would feel like to be first, I wasn’t scared of that prospect any more. And I took that insight and wrote my resignation letter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;meditation-part-2&quot;&gt;Meditation, Part 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I revisited meditation last year when I got a guided meditation app. This was a lot more relaxing as I placed myself in the guide’s practice. I dedicated a chunk of time each morning to practice. If I couldn’t practice at home, I’d take the time on my train ride to work to do it. The app was more motivating, obtaining badges and tracking my progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My practice was less examination of emotion than it was a stress reliever. The rider was able to spend more time working with the elephant, and the elephant sensed the rider was less stressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a long vacation, I stopped. I didn’t want to meditate around friends. When I came home, I dropped the practice. But now as I’m writing this, I may give it a 4th chance because I recognize the benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rider holds the reins of the elephant, but the elephant overpowers the rider. When the rider is too stubborn to acknowledge the elephant, the elephant dictates the outcome. Many times, this is the voice of instant gratification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the rider can notice the elephant’s resistance, the rider’s best option is to roll with it. Now, ask yourself, how can I work with the elephant, and not against it? As the rider, we have the ability to plan ahead and take lessons learned from past failures. Now apply that to your everyday conflicts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://gallery.tinyletterapp.com/b7acb1dd09358f1ed19f16a562a005fc08d42511/images/3e53e436-af9a-4cb7-87b6-188d75e0bfd9.png&quot; alt=&quot;Sample Letter&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="letters" /><category term="season_2" /><category term="letters" /><summary></summary></entry></feed>
